Phonics, which involves sounding out words syllable by syllable, is the best way to teach children to read.
自然拼读法需要逐个音节地把单词拼读出来，是教孩子阅读的最佳方法。
But in many classrooms, this can be a dirty word.
但在许多课堂上，这却是个遭人忌讳的字眼。
So much so that some teachers have had to sneak phonics teaching materials into the classroom.
这种忌讳之深，以至于有些教师不得不把自然拼读法的教学材料偷偷带进教室。
Most American children are taught to read in a way that study after study has found to be wrong.
一项又一项研究都发现，大多数美国孩子学习阅读时所接受的教学方法是错误的。
The consequences of this are striking.
这带来的后果十分惊人。
Less than half of all American adults were proficient readers in 2017.
2017年，在全体美国成年人中，熟练阅读者还不到一半。
American fourth graders rank 15th on the Progress in International Reading Literacy Study, an international exam.
在国际阅读素养进展研究这项国际考试中，美国四年级学生排名第15位。
America is stuck in a debate about teaching children to read that has been going on for decades.
美国深陷一场关于如何教孩子阅读的争论，这场争论已经持续了几十年。
Some advocate teaching symbol-sound relationships (the sound k can be spelled as c, k, ck, or ch), known as phonics.
一些人主张教授符号与读音的对应关系（k这个音可以拼写为c、k、ck或ch），这就是所谓的自然拼读法。
Others support an immersive approach (using pictures of a cat to learn the word cat), known as “whole language”.
另一些人则支持沉浸式方法（借助猫的图片来学习cat这个单词），这就是所谓的“全语言”教学法。
Most teachers today, almost three out of four according to a survey by the EdWeek Research Center in 2019, use a mix called “balanced literacy”.
根据《教育周刊》研究中心2019年的一项调查，如今大多数教师（将近四分之三）采用的是一种名为“平衡读写”的混合教学法。
This combination of methods is ineffective.
这种把多种方法结合在一起的做法是无效的。
“You can’t sprinkle in a little phonics,” says Tenette Smith, executive director of elementary education and reading at Mississippi’s education department.
“不能只是零星地掺进一点自然拼读法，”密西西比州教育厅小学教育与阅读执行主任泰内特·史密斯说。
“It has to be systematic and explicitly taught.”
“必须系统地、明确地教。”
Mississippi, often behind in social policy, has set an example here.
密西西比州在社会政策方面常常落后，但在这方面却树立了榜样。
In a state once notorious for its low reading scores, the Mississippi state legislature passed new literacy standards in 2013.
密西西比州一度以阅读成绩低下而出名，2013年，该州议会通过了新的读写标准。
Since then Mississippi has seen remarkable gains.
自那以后，密西西比州取得了显著的进步。
Its fourth graders have moved from 49th (out of 50 states) to 29th on the National Assessment of Educational Progress, a nationwide exam.
在国家教育进展评估这项全国性考试中，该州四年级学生的排名已从第49位（共50个州）升至第29位。
In 2019 it was the only state to improve its scores.
2019年，密西西比州是唯一一个提高了成绩的州。
For the first time since measurement began, Mississippi’s pupils are now average readers, a remarkable achievement in such a poor state.
自开始测评以来，密西西比州的学生如今首次达到了平均阅读水平，对于这样一个贫穷的州来说，这是一项了不起的成就。
Mississippi’s success is attributed to implementing reading methods supported by a body of research known as the science of reading.
密西西比州的成功归功于实施了有一整套研究作为支撑的阅读教学方法，这套研究被称为“阅读科学”。
In 1997 Congress requested the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development and the Department of Education to convene a National Reading Panel to end the “reading wars” and synthesize the evidence.
1997年，国会要求美国国家儿童健康与人类发展研究所和教育部召集一个国家阅读专家组，以结束“阅读战争”，并综合分析相关证据。
The panel found that phonics, along with explicit instruction in phonemic awareness, fluency and comprehension, worked best.
专家组发现，自然拼读法再加上音位意识、流畅度和理解力方面的明确教学，效果最好。
Yet over two decades on, “balanced literacy” is still being taught in classrooms.
然而，二十多年过去了，课堂上仍在采用“平衡读写”教学法。
But advances in statistics and brain imaging have disproved the whole-language method.
但统计学和脑成像技术的进步已经推翻了全语言教学法。
To the teacher who is a proficient reader, literacy seems like a natural process that requires educated guessing, rather than the deliberate process emphasized by phonics.
在本身就是熟练阅读者的教师看来，读写似乎是一个需要有根据地猜测的自然过程，而不是自然拼读法所强调的那种刻意的过程。
Teachers can imagine that they learned to read through osmosis when they were children.
教师们可能会以为，自己小时候是在潜移默化中学会阅读的。
Without proper training, they bring this to classrooms.
如果没有经过适当的培训，他们就会把这种想法带进课堂。